<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="sect-Release_Notes-Overview">
    <title>Overview</title>
    <para>
        Pardus &PRODVER; contains major improvements over the previous Pardus release &PREVVER;. The following sections provide
        a brief overview of those changes.
    </para>

    <section id="sect-Release_Notes-Hardware_Overview">

        <title>Hardware Overview</title>
        <para>
            Pardus &PRODVER; now supports 64-bit processor architecture which is supported by many new Intel and AMD processors.
        </para>
    </section>
    <section id="sect-Release_Notes-Software_Overview">
        <title>Software Overview</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>Kernel</application> - The latest Linux kernel &KERNELVER; provides an up-to-date hardware support
                    together with a thousand of bug fixes.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>Plymouth</application> - The bootsplash technology used in Pardus &PREVVER; is completely dropped and replaced by the new Plymouth engine.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>YALI</application> - YALI, the installer of Pardus, gained LVM/RAID and UUID support.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>KDE SC</application> - Pardus &PRODVER; comes with the latest KDE Software Compilation, KDE SC &KDEVER;. The base packages also contains numerous backports and fixes which will improve the stability of your desktop experience significantly.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>Kaptan</application> - Kaptan, the desktop customization tool of Pardus, now optionally captures your picture and sets it as your avatar in KDE.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>NetworkManager</application> - GNOME NetworkManager 0.8.2 is now the default networking backend in Pardus &PRODVER;. Users are now able to set up their HSPA/CDMA/VPN networks together with the already supported Ethernet and 802.11 WLAN networks.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>GTK Oxygen style</application> - All GTK applications are now rendered with Oxygen style thanks to the <emphasis>oxygen-gtk</emphasis> project. This brings a huge improvement to the user interface consistency.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>LibreOffice</application> - LibreOffice, an Open Source personal productivity suite sponsored by the Document Foundation, is now the default Office Suite in Pardus &PRODVER;.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>
</section>
