<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="sect-Release_Notes-Welcome_to_Pardus">
    <title>Welcome to Pardus &PRODVER;</title>
    <para>
        Welcome to Pardus &PRODVER;, the latest release of Pardus, a powerful, KDE-focused Linux distribution.
    </para>

    <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_Pardus">
        <title>What is Pardus?</title>
        <para>
            Pardus is an open-source, freely distributable, GPL (General Public License) licensed user-friendly
            GNU/Linux distribution with many usability, hardware compatibility, stability and security enhancements.
        </para>
        <para>
            The Pardus project is sponsored by the <emphasis>Center of Research for Advanced Technologies of Informatics and Information Security (BILGEM)</emphasis>,
            an affiliate of the <emphasis>Scientific and Technological Research Council of Turkey (TUBITAK)</emphasis>.
        </para>
        <para>
            The aim of the Pardus distribution is to offer people a stable, reliable, easy-to-use and
            feature-rich computer experience by providing modern and popular open-source software. The
            developers are also putting an additional effort to make Pardus run on a wide range of
            hardware.
        </para>
        <para>
            The project is named after the latin (and scientific) name for the Anatolian leopard, <emphasis>Panthera pardus tulliana</emphasis>.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="sect-Release_Notes-How_Can_I_Try_Pardus">
        <title>How Can I Try Pardus?</title>
        <para>
            You can try Pardus either by installing it on your computer or running the Live version
            without touching your hard disk. You can boot Pardus from an optical drive as well as from
            USB mass storage devices like external hard drives and USB flash drives.
        </para>
        <para>
            Both the installation and live version images exceeds the size of a regular CD
            so if you are willing to use an optical drive for booting Pardus, you currently have to
            use DVD media to burn the images.
        </para>
        <para>
            Note that the boot order in your system's BIOS software should be set with the optical drive
            or USB mass storage device as the first device in order to boot from the installation or
            the live medium. On newer systems, the boot order can also be changed by pressing a key
            (generally F8 on desktop systems) while booting.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="sect-Release_Notes-More_Information">
        <title>More Information</title>
        <para>
            Visit the official web site <ulink url="http://www.pardus.org.tr/eng">http://www.pardus.org.tr/eng</ulink>
            for more information.
        </para>
    </section>

    <section id="sect-Release_Notes-Feedback">
        <title>Feedback</title>
        <para>
            Visit <ulink url="http://bugs.pardus.org.tr">http://bugs.pardus.org.tr</ulink>
            to report a bug, send a bug fix or suggest improvements about Pardus.We would
            like to thank all of our users and community members for their valuable contributions
            which help improving Pardus, Linux and free software worldwide.
        </para>
    </section>
</section>
