<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Release_Notes.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New">
    <title>What is New?</title>

    <section id="sect-Release_Notes-Updates_in_Pardus_Technologies">
        <title>Updates in Pardus Technologies</title>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Installation">
            <title>YALI</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>YALI</emphasis>, the installer of Pardus, gained LVM/RAID and UUID support.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        The user interface is completely redesigned to improve the usability.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Users are now able to select between Open Source and proprietary drivers for their
                        NVIDIA video adapters.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_First_boot">
            <title>First Boot</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Some of the settings which were asked during the installation in Pardus &PREVVER; are now moved into a different application which shows up once during the first boot after the installation.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Kaptan">
            <title>Kaptan</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Kaptan</emphasis>, the desktop customization tool of Pardus, now optionally captures your picture and sets it as your avatar in KDE.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Users are now able to select their preferred icon theme which will be used in their KDE desktop environment.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        The user interface is completely redesigned to improve the usability.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Pisi">
            <title>Pisi</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        <emphasis>Pisi</emphasis> now internally uses XZ as the default compression algorithm.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Binary package names now reflects the architecture and the distribution release for which the
                        package is built.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Various speed enhancements has been done in the core components for a better package management experience.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Package_Manager">
            <title>Package Manager</title>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        Users are now able to vote for a package and see the screenshots of graphical applications shipped within
                        packages.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        The graphical user interface is redesigned to improve the usability. Various speed enhancements has been
                        done for a better graphical package management experience.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
                        A lot of KDE integration work has been done including the usage of KDE system tray.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
    </section>

    <section id="sect-Release_Notes-Updates_in_Core_Components">
        <title>Updates in Core Components</title>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>Kernel</application> - The Linux kernel shipped with Pardus &PRODVER; is &KERNELVER; which is the latest
                    stable kernel released on 2011/01/05.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>Plymouth</application> - The bootsplash technology used in Pardus &PREVVER; is completely dropped and replaced by the new Plymouth engine.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>Python</application> - Python is updated to &PYTHONVER;.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>Perl</application> - Perl is updated to &PERLVER;.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>X.org</application> - xorg-server is updated to &XORGVER;, improvements to the automatic driver configuration mechanism has been done by our developers.
                </para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>
                    <application>TeX Live</application> - TeX Live documentation stack is updated to &TEXLIVEVER;.
                </para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
    </section>

    <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Desktop_Experience">
        <title>Desktop Experience</title>
        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_KDE">
            <title>Changes in KDE Desktop Environment</title>
            <para>
                Pardus &PRODVER; comes with the latest KDE Software Compilation, KDE SC &KDEVER;. The base packages also contains numerous backports and fixes which will improve the stability of your desktop experience significantly.
            </para>
            <para>
                KDE SC &KDEVER; brings more performance and stability to the desktop experience. Support for WebKit, improved user experience for netbooks, a new high-speed cache allowing fast access to resources stored on disk are among the new features of this version.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Visual">
            <title>Visual Enhancements</title>
            <para>
                All GTK applications are now rendered with Oxygen style thanks to the <emphasis>oxygen-gtk</emphasis> project. This brings a huge improvement to the user interface consistency.
            </para>
            <para>
                Milky icon theme especially designed for Pardus is shipped within the installation image. Users can set this icon theme through <emphasis>Kaptan</emphasis> or <emphasis>System Settings</emphasis>.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Network_Management">
            <title>Network Management</title>
            <para>
                Besides switching to GNOME NetworkManager as the default networking backend, Pardus &PRODVER; comes with a heavily improved and modified KDE Network Management
                tool and plasmoid to give their users a much more consistent networking experience.
            </para>
            <para>
                With this new networking backend, users are now able to easily set up their Ethernet (With support for 802.1x authentication),
                802.11 Wireless (With support for WEP/WPA/WPA2/WPA-EAP and 802.1x authentication), EDGE/3G/CDMA and VPN networks.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Default_Applications">
            <title>Default Applications</title>
            <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Default_Applications_Mozilla_Firefox">
                <title>Mozilla Firefox</title>
                <para>
                    Pardus &PRODVER; comes with Mozilla Firefox &FIREFOXVER; as the default web browser application.
                    New features of this Firefox release include Firefox Panorama, application tabs, a redesigned extension
                    manager, Jetpack extensions support, integration with Firefox Sync, and support for multitouch displays.
                </para>
            </section>
            <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Default_Applications_Clementine">
                <title>Clementine</title>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>Clementine</emphasis>, a cross-platform music player based on Amarok 1.4 is set as the default audio playing application as it
                    is well maintained and lightweight.
                </para>
            </section>
            <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Default_Applications_SMplayer">
                <title>SMPlayer</title>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>SMplayer</emphasis>, a Qt based frontend for MPlayer is set as the default Video/VCD/DVD playing application as it is well integrated
                    with KDE desktop environment in terms of usability and graphical user interface and supports playing a wide range of video file
                    types thanks to the MPlayer backend.
                </para>
            </section>
            <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Default_Applications_KsCD">
                <title>KsCD</title>
                <para>
                    <emphasis>KsCD</emphasis>, is set as the default Audio CD playing application.
                </para>
            </section>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Browsers">
            <title>Web Browsers</title>
            <para>
                Although not included in the installation images, a wide range of web browsers including Chromium browser, rekonq, Arora and Opera are
                available for installation through the package manager.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_System_Settings">
            <title>System Settings</title>
            <para>
                <emphasis>Panda</emphasis> (Pardus alternative driver administration) is a new System Settings module which allows users to change the driver
                between Open Source and proprietary one for NVIDIA and ATI display adapters.
            </para>
            <para>
                Users are now able to set up their Bluetooth devices, Wacom tablets and Synaptics touchpads through System Settings.
            </para>
            <para>
                The default language used throughout the whole system can now be changed through the locale settings section.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Office">
            <title>Office Suite</title>
            <para>
                <emphasis>LibreOffice</emphasis>, an Open Source personal productivity suite sponsored by the Document Foundation, is now the default Office Suite in Pardus &PRODVER;.
            </para>
        </section>

        <section id="sect-Release_Notes-What_is_New_Games">
            <title>Games</title>
            <para>
                Pardus &PRODVER; continues the tradition of giving importance to the quality of games offered to their users. The default installation now includes the board and logic games provided by the <application>kdegames</application> package.
            </para>
        </section>

    </section>

    <section id="sect-Release_Notes-Other_Changes">
        <title>Other Changes</title>
        <para>
            Firefox gets new stable release rapidly. &FIREFOXVER; release presents many new features like the new
            interface of the browser as well as plugin management new interface, tab grouping, bookmarks between
            computers, passwords and history matching, a new plug-in interface. HTML5, CSS3 and WebM technology
            supports are also most important features for the developers.
        </para>
    </section>
</section>
